{"tossups": [{"question": "Stanley Forman won a Pulitzer for a picture in this city that shows Joseph Rakes attacking Ted Landsmark with an American flag.<em> Morgan v. Hennigan</em> ruled that this city\u2019s busing policy had created de facto segregation. In 1998, a federal court ruled that this city\u2019s Latin school, the oldest public school in the United States, could no longer consider race when accepting students. For the point, name this city that, in 2018, stopped honoring racist owner Tom Yawkey with a street name outside Fenway Park, where the Red Sox play in Massachusetts.", "answer": "<b> Boston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Note: two answers required. One of these countries declared independence from the other on February 27, 1844, from La Puerta del Conde. Shortly after, Emperor Faustin I, a dictator of one of these two countries, launched a failed invasion of the other, led by Buenaventura Baez. In 1937, a dictator known as \u201cEl Jefe\u201d [ell HAY-fay] ordered the Parsley Massacre along the frontier between these countries. Rafael Trujillo [troo-HEE-yo] and Papa Doc Duvalier [doo-vahl-YAY] were 20th century dictators of, for the point, what two Caribbean nations that share the island of Hispaniola?", "answer": "<b> Haiti</b> and the<b> Dominican Republic</b> (accept in either order)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Many of these people\u2019s<em> stanitsa</em> villages were burned to the ground during a \u201cRed Terror\u201d named for their homeland. The Yaik sub-group of these people successfully recruited the Baskir people in a rebellion named for its leader, Yemelyan Pugachev. Much of the White Army that formed to resist the Bolsheviks in 1918 was made up of the Don and Kuban subsets of these people. For the point, name this military class of steppe horsemen of Ukraine and Southern Russia.", "answer": "<b> Cossack</b>s", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This entrepreneur accused the market for not caring \u201cwhat\u2019s best for us\u201d in his 2018 book<em> War on</em> <em>the Normal People</em>. Venture for America, a non-profit to \u201crevitalize American cities,\u201d was founded by this politician. This politician claimed that he was the opposite of Trump because he was an \u201cAsian man who likes math.\u201d A $1000 stipend per month for all citizens is a central policy of, for the point, what 2020 Democratic presidential hopeful who supports a Universal Basic Income?", "answer": "Andrew<b> Yang</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This artist\u2019s painting of six cloth inspectors is known either as<em> The Sampling Officials</em> or as<em> Syndics</em> <em>of the Drapers\u201d Guild</em>. A boy carrying a horn of gunpowder appears on the left side of a painting by this artist. A man wearing a yellow outfit and holding a shortened pike is shown in a painting by this man that depicts the militia company of Frans Banning Cocq [COKE]. For the point, name this Dutch Golden Age artist of<em> The Night Watch</em>.", "answer": "<b> Rembrandt</b> van Rijn", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This man\u2019s son was labeled the \u201cUnfortunate\u201d after being exiled from Venice and eventually drowning in a river while fleeing from the Battle of Garigliano. In the aftermath of this man\u2019s death, Girolamo Savonarola started a Bonfire of the Vanities. With the blessing of Pope Sixtus IV, this man and his brother Giuliano were targeted in the Pazzi Conspiracy. Florence was ruled by, for the point, what grandson of Cosimo de Medici, a patron of the arts known as \u201cthe Magnificent?\u201d", "answer": "<b> Lorenzo</b> the Magnificent (accept<b> Lorenzo</b> de Medici)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A popular hiking trail in this mountain range passes through a pass nicknamed the \u201cDead Woman\u201dand often begins near the city of Ollantaytambo. The terminus of that trail visits a \u201clost city\u201d in this mountain range whose terraces and mortar-less masonry were rediscovered by Hiram Bingham. The city of Machu Picchu is one of many Inca ruins in, for the point, what major mountain range of South America?", "answer": "<b> Andes</b> Mountains", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {}, {"question": "In this work, a man tells his friend that he may have agreed to a 999-year marriage, but he has the option to cancel every month. This work inspired an adaptation set in the Vietnam War,<em> Miss Saigon</em>. After meeting Kate, the title character of this opera puts an American flag in her son\u2019s hand before committing seppuku. For the point, name this Giacomo Puccini opera about a Japanese woman who kills herself after being abandoned by her American husband.", "answer": "<b> Madame Butterfly</b> (or<b> Madama Butterfly</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {"question": "John Rabe was elected the leader of a safety zone in this city, partly due to his status in the Nazi Party. In a 1997 book, Iris Chang labeled an event in this city \u201cThe Forgotten Holocaust of World War II.\u201dThis city was besieged by Prince Asaka, who may have given an order to \u201ckill the captives,\u201d prompting atrocities like a beheading contest. For the point, name this Chinese city, the site of a 1937 massacre by Japanese forces.", "answer": "<b> Nanking</b> (accept<b> Nanjing</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A young Martin Luther King Jr. sang in a church choir for this film\u2019s premiere in Atlanta. After a year long search, the largely unknown British actress Vivian Leigh was cast as this film\u2019s leading lady. Hattie McDaniel, who won an Oscar for her role as Mammy, was unable to attend a premiere of this film because it was segregated. For the point, name this 1939 film, based on a novel by Margaret Mitchell, about the life of Scarlett O\u2019Hara during the Civil War.", "answer": "<b> Gone with the Wind</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {"question": "This event is commemorated by a statue in Seelow Heights that depicts a soldier wielding a PPSh [P-P-S-H]. A photograph of a soldier during this event had to be altered because his multiple watches proved that he had been looting. Karl D\u00a8onitz was made President of the Flensburg Government during this event. To signal the completion of this event, soldiers who had crossed the Moltke Bridge raised their flag over the Reichstag. For the point, name this 1945 event in which Soviet forces captured the capital of Nazi Germany.", "answer": "the<b> fall of Berlin</b> (accept<b> Battle of Berlin</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "With novelist Romain Rolland, this man developed the idea that religious sentiments arise from an\u201coceanic feeling\u201d of unity. This man\u2019s daughter Anna was among the first researchers to discuss defense mechanisms. This psychologist claimed that children exhibit sexual attraction to their opposite-sex parent in his book<em> The Interpretation of Dreams</em>. For the point, name this Austrian formulator of the Oedipus complex and pioneer of psychoanalysis.", "answer": "Sigmund<b> Freud</b> (or Sigismund Schlomo<b> Freud</b>)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {"question": "The European Union deployed peacekeeping troops to the eastern portion of this country in the Ituri War. After the outbreak of the Katanga Civil War in this country, its prime minister Patrice Lumumba was captured and executed by Belgian officers. A military dictatorship under Joseph Mobutu took over this country in the 1960s and later changed its name to Zaire. For the point, name this central African country that renamed its capital from L\u00b4eopoldville to Kinshasa in 1966.", "answer": "<b> Democratic Republic of the Congo</b> (or<b> DRC</b>; prompt on \u201cCongo\u201d; do not accept or prompt on \u201cRepublic of the Congo\u201d alone)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This politician fell for a hoax accusing Franklin Pierce of plotting against the United States, resulting in some of his powers being transferred to the War Department. In a debate over the Compromise of 1850, this man argued that new territories were governed by a \u201chigher law than the constitution.\u201d George F. Robinson was injured defending this man from an attempted assassination by Lewis Powell. For the point, name this Secretary of State under Abraham Lincoln and Andrew Johnson who orchestrated the purchase of Alaska.", "answer": "William H.<b> Seward</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "The Ocala Demands called for the reclamation of land specifically owned by this industry. Monroe Heath, then the Mayor of Chicago, recruited five thousand men to suppress this industry\u2019s 1877 \u201cGreat Strike.\u201d Leland Stanford was a member of the \u201cBig Four,\u201d a group that dominated this industry west of the Mississippi. The Interstate Commerce Commission was established to regulate this industry. Cornelius Vanderbilt made his fortune in, for the point, what industry used to transport freight over land?", "answer": "<b> rail</b>road", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Daniel Dennett discussed this person\u2019s \u201cdangerous idea.\u201d This person\u2019s ideas were championed by Thomas Huxley, who was nicknamed this person\u2019s \u201cbulldog.\u201d Herbert Spencer developed a \u201csocial\u201d form of this person\u2019s thought. This scientist names the population of finches on the Galapagos, which he studied during his second voyage on the HMS<em> Beagle</em>. For the point, name this biologist and author of<em> On the</em> <em>Origin of Species</em> who developed the theory of evolution by natural selection.", "answer": "Charles<b> Darwin</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "Revolutions in the Congo and Cuba were aided by, for the point, what Argentine Marxist revolutionary who worked with Fidel Castro?", "answer": "Ernesto \u201cChe\u201d<b> Guevara</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "For the point, name this leader who fought the Royalists in the English Civil War.", "answer": "Oliver<b> Cromwell</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this play\u2019s opening scene, two men berate a cobbler for taking a day off from work to attend a celebratory parade. A morally conflicted character in this play is devastated by the suicide of his wife, Portia. A soothsayer tells the title character of this play to \u201cbeware the Ides of March,\u201d a warning that comes true when he is assassinated by Cassius and Brutus. For the point, name this William Shakespeare play about a Roman statesman.", "answer": "<b> Julius Caesar</b>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Drama"}, {"question": "Forces from a kingdom in this modern-day country defeated Michael III of Bulgaria to secure Epirus at the Battle of Velbazhd. An empire based in this country exploited a civil war between John V [the fifth] Palailogos and Anna of Savoy to conquer Macedonia. The Austro-Hungarian Empire declared war against this home of Gavrilo Princip to spark World War I. For the point, name this country that reclaimed its historic capital of Belgrade after breaking away from Yugoslavia.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Serbia</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This President secured American control of land around Guantanamo Bay after withdrawing troops from Cuba. This President began codifying his foreign policy after denouncing an Anglo-German blockade of Venezuela. The Great White Fleet was tasked by this man to circumnavigate the world as a show of American power. For the point, name this President who described his foreign policy as \u201cspeak softly and carry a big stick.\u201d", "answer": "<b> T</b>heodore<b> Roosevelt</b> (accept<b> T</b>eddy<b> Roosevelt</b>; prompt on Roosevelt)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In a speech given in the aftermath of this event, a politician reinforced his Four Cardinal Principles and claimed that military intervention was justified. A ten meter tall paper-mache statue called the Goddess of Democracy was constructed during this event. In a picture from this event, a man with a bag in his hand refuses to move out of the way of encroaching tanks. For the point, name this 1989 event in which thousands of people protested in a Beijing square.", "answer": "<b> Tienanmen Square</b> protests (accept<b> June 4th Movement</b>; accept<b> liusi shijian</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "At this city\u2019s Riverside church, Martin Luther King delivered his \u201cBeyond Vietnam\u201d speech. David Miller became the first person to burn his draft card while at a rally in this city against the Armed Forces Induction Center on Whitehall Street. Construction workers in this city carried out the Hard Hat Riot when they attacked students protesting the Kent State shootings who had gathered at Wall Street. For the point, name this city where the Vietnam War was protested in Times Square.", "answer": "<b> New York</b> City (or<b> NYC</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Agents sponsored by his rival killed this man with an ice-axe while in exile in Mexico City. For the point, name this early communist revolutionary and ally of Lenin who was opposed by Stalin.", "answer": "Leon<b> Trotsky</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "After being recognized by a pumpkin seed vendor in Parral, this man was assassinated by supporters of Alvaro Obregon. John Pershing led an expedition to capture this man. With his Division of the North, this man allied with Emiliano Zapata against the regime of Victoriano Huerta. For the point, name this Mexican revolutionary who raided Columbus, New Mexico in 1916.", "answer": "Francisco \u201cPancho\u201d<b> Villa</b> (accept Jose Doroteo<b> Arango Arambula</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This building is home to Emmanuel Leutze\u2019s [loyt-zuh\u2019s] painting<em> Westward the Course of Empire</em> <em>Takes Its Way</em>. A Constantino Brumidi \u201cApotheosis\u201d decorates the oculus of a dome in this building, whose primary architect was William Thornton. John Quincy Adams was inaugurated in this structure\u2019s Statutory Hall, which is home to the<em> Car of History</em> clock depicting Clio recording the proceedings of the House of Representatives. For the point, name this building whose chambers host Congress.", "answer": "U.S.<b> Capitol</b> Building", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "During one conflict in this country, Jacob Smith ordered his troops to \u201ckill everyone over the age of ten.\u201d The proclamation of the Malolos Constitution, which established this country\u2019s First Republic, sparked a war with the United States that ended with the capture of Emilio Aguinaldo. George Dewey captured this modern-day country after defeating its Spanish defenders at an 1898 naval battle. For the point, name this Southeast Asian country, the site of the Battle of Manila Bay.", "answer": "<b> Philippines</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A general in this country seized power after assassinating William R. Tolbert and formed the People\u2019s Redemption Council. In 2018, the President of this country, George Weah, reduced his salary by 25% to confront its broken economy. The Libyan-trained Charles Taylor overthrew Samuel Doe in this country, sparking a 1989 civil war. The American Colonization Society helped thousands of free blacks immigrate to what is now, for the point, what West African country with capital Monrovia?", "answer": "Republic of<b> Liberia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This city was founded by Belloveso, a leader of the Insubri Celts, who legendarily saw a \u201chalf-woolen bear\u201d that he then made the city\u2019s symbol. Emperor Maximian ruled the Western Roman Empire from this city before moving the capital to Ravenna due to invading Visigoths. In 313 AD, Licinius and Constantine I met in this city to discuss Galerius\u201d Edict of Toleration. For the point, name this city in Lombardy that names an edict that granted Christianity legal status in the Roman Empire.", "answer": "<b> Milan</b> (accept<b> Mediolanum</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This state\u2019s Black Republicans merged with the Populists to create the Fusion Party. In 1871, the governor of this state, William Holden, was impeached for suppressing KKK activity. Democrats in this state led by Alfred Waddell attacked<em> The Daily Record</em> newspaper during the Wilmington insurrection of 1898, which disenfranchised blacks throughout this state in cities like Asheville and Greensboro. For the point, name this southern state where the Negro Voting League formed in Raleigh.", "answer": "<b> North Carolina</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This country ceded territorial claims after being defeated by the British in the Duar War. In 1910, this country secured its independence by signing a treaty at Punakha Dzong. In 2003, mountaineering was banned in this country out of respect for spiritual customs, protecting Gangkhar Puensum as the tallest unclimbed mountain in the world. This country, whose government measures Gross National Happiness, is located between the Indian state of Sikkim and Tibet. For the point, name this South Asian country governed from Thimphu.", "answer": "Kingdom of<b> Bhutan</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "This modern-day country was once home to the Srivijaya kingdom, which was significantly weakened after a series of raids from the nearby Chola Empire. From the 14th to the 16th centuries, the Majapahit Empire was the most dominant state in this country\u2019s present-day territory. The temple of Borobudur was built in the territory of, for the point, what country where the Mataram Sultanate came under Islamic influence that had spread to Java from Sumatra?", "answer": "<b> Indonesia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "During this period, the illiterate freeman Black Harry Hosier was nicknamed the \u201cGreat American Orator\u201d by Benjamin Rush. This period sparked the creation of \u201ccamp meetings\u201d including a massive one hosted in Cane Ridge, Kentucky. Charles Finney described a portion of western New York as the\u201cburned-over district\u201d due to its role in this period. The Seventh-day Adventists were established during, for the point, what early 19th century period of religious revival in the United States?", "answer": "<b> Second Great Awakening</b> (prompt on Great Awakening)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This person determined that the sum of the squared reciprocals of the natural numbers equaled pi squared over six. This person, who was given a job in Berlin by Frederick the Great, names a path in a graph that visits every edge. A staggeringly large number of mathematical theorems and concepts are named for the second person to discover them after this man. The Seven Bridges of Konigsberg problem was formulated by, for the point, what Swiss mathematician who names a number approximately equal to 2.718, the base of the natural logarithm.", "answer": "Leonhard<b> Euler</b> [oy-ler]", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Math"}, {}, {"question": "This man is credited with spreading the worship of the shamaness-turned-sea goddess Mazu across Asia. The Mao Kun map accurately depicts this man\u2019s journey to cities on the Swahili Coast like Malindi and Mombasa. This man was gifted a giraffe by the Sultan of Bengal which he promptly brought back to the Yongle Emperor. For the point, name this Muslim eunuch, a 15th century Chinese admiral who led many treasure voyages for the Ming.", "answer": "<b> Zheng</b> He (accept<b> Cheng</b> Ho)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This politician warned that the North would \u201cmove with the steady momentum and perseverance of a mighty avalanche\u201d after being removed from office in 1861. This man, angry with his letters being ignored, beat William Stanberry with a cane. During one battle, this man ordered the destruction of Vince\u2019s Bridge to trap his enemy in the Brazos River. This commander utilized two cannons called the Twin Sisters to win the Battle of San Jacinto. For the point, name this first President of the Republic of Texas.", "answer": "Sam<b> Houston</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man saved Rome from the Lombards even though the exarch of Ravenna from the Byzantine Empire claimed control over negotiations. In the<em> Institutes</em>, John Calvin called this man the \u201cLast Good Pope.\u201d This pope, who fought Arianism in the Visigothic Kingdom, successfully converted the Anglo-Saxons to Christianity. For the point, name this \u201cGreat\u201d 6th century pope who, according to legend, invented a monophonic plain chant to be used in Catholic church music.", "answer": "Pope<b> Gregory I</b> (or<b> Gregory the Great</b>; accept<b> Gregorian chant</b> after \u201cchant\u201d is read; prompt on Gregory)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2017, Mauricio Macri revoked this man\u2019s Order of the Liberator General San Martin award due to human rights abuses. This current chair of the Non-Aligned Movement funneled funds for food to his associates via his CLAP social program. This man was accused of fixing a 2018 election, causing the National Assembly to declare his opponent, Juan Guaid\u00b4o, acting President. For the point, name this current President of Venezuela.", "answer": "Nicolas<b> Maduro</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this founder of the Workers\u201d Party of Korea who was succeeded by his son, Kim Jong-il.", "answer": "<b> Kim Il-sung</b> (prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In a failed attempt to capture this man, Allan Pinkerton detonated an incendiary device that gravely wounded Zerelda Samuel. Thomas Crittenden, the governor of Missouri, immediately pardoned the man who killed this outlaw. During one event, this man failed to rob a bank in Northfield, Minnesota, leading to the near-destruction of the gang he established with Cole Younger and his brother, Frank. For the point, name this American outlaw who was killed by Robert Ford.", "answer": "Jesse<b> James</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {"question": "This party collapsed after only its second national election when a ticket of John Hale and George Washington Julian failed to capture even 5% of the popular vote. The Barnburners helped form this party after the Democratic Convention refused to endorse the Wilmot Proviso. This party failed to secure any electoral votes in the Election of 1848 despite running former President Martin van Buren. For the point, name this short-lived, single issue party that opposed the expansion of slavery.", "answer": "<b> Free Soil</b> Party", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "A 1952 novel centered on this activity chronicles the attempted murder-suicide of Harriet Bird, based on the life of Eddie Waitkus. Franklin Pierce Adams wrote a poem about this activity\u2019s \u201cSad Lexicon\u201dthat opens, \u201cThese are the saddest of possible words.\u201d Roy Hobbs leads the fictional New York Knights to a 17-game winning streak in this sport in Bernard Malamud\u2019s novel<em> The Natural</em>. Ernest Thayer wrote a poem about this sport in which angry supporters of the Mudville Nine shout \u201cKill him! Kill the umpire!\u201dFor the point, name this sport, the focus of \u201cCasey at the Bat.\u201d", "answer": "<b> baseball</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "A statue of one of these people in Hunan characterizes his many blessings as his \u201cthousand arms and thousand eyes.\u201d Dizang, Puxian, and Wenshu are three of these people often grouped with Avalokiteshvara [ah-vah-loh-kee-tesh-vah-rah], who became known as Guanyin in China, and who symbolizes ultimate compassion. Another of these people, Vajrapani, legendarily guided Gautama Buddha in his journeys. For the point, name these figures from Buddhism who put off becoming Buddhas to act as guides for others wishing to achieve enlightenment.", "answer": "<b> bodhisattva</b> (do not accept or prompt on \u201cbuddha\u201d)", "metadata": "Religion - Religion"}, {"question": "This event prompted intervention by a naval squadron led by Thomas Larimore. The instigator of this rebellion may have been upset due to not being invited to join the fur trade of the Green Springs circle. After the initial leader of this event died of dysentery, he was replaced by John Ingram. Supporters of this revolt criticized William Berkeley for not properly responding to attacks by the Doeg people. Jamestown was burned during, for the point, what 1676 rebellion in colonial Virginia?", "answer": "<b> Bacon\u2019s</b> Rebellion", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In Egypt, Solon hears the story of this city, which was founded by the descendants of a Greek god and the mortal Cleito. Plato\u2019s dialogues<em> Timaeus</em> and<em> Critias</em> describe how this city loses a great war against Athens. Along with the word \u201cnew,\u201d this city titles a Utopian novel by Sir Francis Bacon. For the point, name this fictional city that, in popular culture, is often depicted as an island or lost realm under the sea.", "answer": "<b> Atlantis</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Darius Couch was so disgusted by his commanding officer\u2019s behavior at this battle that he resigned his major general commission. Cadmus Wilcox forced the Battle of Salem Church to delay John Sedgwick\u2019s forces from reinforcing one side in this battle. This battle started after forces under Joseph Hooker crossed the Rappahannock River to engage Robert E. Lee. Stonewall Jackson was wounded by friendly fire during, for the point, what 1863 Confederate victory in Virginia?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Chancellorsville</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "An invasion of this country was temporarily halted by the Mannerheim Line. In this country, soldiers developed the \u201cMolotov Cocktail\u201d to destroy enemy tanks. A sniper from this country, Simo Hayha, was nicknamed \u201cThe White Death\u201d by the Red Army. This country was forced to cede Karelia after losing the Winter War; it was invaded by the Soviet Union due to its proximity to Leningrad. For the point, name this country that was caught off guard by the sudden bombing of Helsinki.", "answer": "<b> Finland</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "This country was the site of the Mareth Line, a \u201cMaginot Line in the desert.\u201d Poorly led US troops suffered a defeat in this country at the hands of the German Afrika Korps led by Erwin Rommel at the Kasserine Pass. This modern-day country is the site of the ancient Phoenician ruins of Utica and a city legendarily founded by Dido on the Mediterranean. For the point, name this north African country where the ruins of Carthage can be found between Libya and Algeria.", "answer": "<b> Tunisia</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This dynasty secured a foothold in Central Asia after defeating the Xiongnu people at the Battle of Mobei. The Trung Sisters launched a failed revolt against this dynasty in Vietnam. The tyrant Dong Zhuo briefly controlled this dynasty after deposing Emperor Shao. This dynasty employed He Jin to suppress the Yellow Turban Rebellion. Liu Bang and Wu Di ruled this dynasty centered on Chang\u2019an. The Qin dynasty was succeeded by, for the point, what dynasty that lends its name to China\u2019s largest ethnic group?", "answer": "<b> Han</b> dynasty", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "In William of Poitiers\u201d recount of this battle, he notes the winning commander used a holy banner given to him by Pope Alexander II. Retreating forces from this battle were trapped in a ditch called the Malfosse. In the prelude to this battle, Harald Hardradawas killed at the Battle of Stamford Bridge. The Bayeux Tapestry shows Harold Godwinson being shot in the eye during this battle. William the Conqueror won, for the point, what 1066 battle that secured the Norman conquest of England?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Hastings</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "For the point, name this southern African ethnic group whose empire was once led by Shaka.", "answer": "ama<b>Zulu</b> people", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}